const quizSets = {
  quiz1: [
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a consumptive value?",
      options: [
        "timber",
        "firewood",
        "non-timber forest products",
        "education",
      ],
      answer: "education",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a forest type found in India?",
      options: [
        "Mediterranean dry",
        "Tropical dry",
        "Montane temperate",
        "Alpine",
      ],
      answer: "Mediterranean dry",
    },
    {
      question:
        '“Plant community, predominantly comprised of trees and other woody vegetation, usually with a closed canopy" is',
      options: [
        "silvicultural definition of forests",
        "FAO definition of forests",
        "legal definition of forests",
        "ecological definition of forests",
      ],
      answer: "ecological definition of forests",
    },
    {
      question:
        "According to the Supreme Court, the word forest must be understood according to its",
      options: [
        "biological meaning",
        "ecological meaning",
        "silvicultural meaning",
        "dictionary meaning",
      ],
      answer: "dictionary meaning",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a use value?",
      options: [
        "direct value",
        "indirect value",
        "option value",
        "existence value",
      ],
      answer: "existence value",
    },
    {
      question: "According to the Supreme Court, the term forest land includes",
      options: [
        "some area recorded as forest in the Government record according to ownership",
        "any area recorded as forest in the Government record according to ownership",
        "some area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
        "any area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
      ],
      answer:
        "any area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
    },
    {
      question: "Tropical moist forests do not include",
      options: [
        "broadleaved forests",
        "wet evergreen forests",
        "semi-evergreen forests",
        "moist deciduous forests",
      ],
      answer: "broadleaved forests",
    },
    {
      question:
        "The value of leaving use and non-use values for offspring’s or future generations is called",
      options: [
        "altruistic value",
        "bequest value",
        "existence value",
        "option value",
      ],
      answer: "bequest value",
    },
    {
      question: "The term 'forest' originates from",
      options: [
        "Latin foris meaning outside",
        "Greek foris meaning outside",
        "Latin foris meaning trees",
        "Greek foris meaning trees",
      ],
      answer: "Latin foris meaning outside",
    },
    {
      question:
        "The value derived from the knowledge of use of resources by others in the current generation is called",
      options: [
        "altruistic value",
        "bequest value",
        "existence value",
        "option value",
      ],
      answer: "altruistic value",
    },
  ],
  quiz2: [
    {
      question: "Lithosere is an example of",
      options: ["hydrosere", "xerosere", "psammosere", "halosere"],
      answer: "xerosere",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which of these depicts correctly the lithosere primary succession?",
      options: [
        "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Rock → Foliose lichen → Crustose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Moss → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Rock → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Shrub → Herbaceous stage → Moss → Woodland → Climax",
      ],
      answer:
        "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
    },
    {
      question: "At compensation point,",
      options: [
        "photosynthesis = respiration",
        "photosynthesis > respiration",
        "photosynthesis < respiration",
        "none of these",
      ],
      answer: "photosynthesis = respiration",
    },
    {
      question:
        "The study of life history / general features of forest crops with respect to environmental factors is called",
      options: ["foresti-culture", "monoculture", "silviculture", "silvics"],
      answer: "silvics",
    },
    {
      question: "A climax caused by wildfires is an example of",
      options: [
        "climatic climax",
        "edaphic climax",
        "disclimax",
        "catastrophic climax",
      ],
      answer: "catastrophic climax",
    },
    {
      question: "Net primary productivity is given by",
      options: ["APAR + LUE", "APAR X LUE", "APAR - LUE", "APAR ÷ LUE"],
      answer: "APAR X LUE",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Practical application of scientific, technical and economic principles of forestry comes under which branch of forestry?",
      options: [
        "forest management",
        "forest economics",
        "forest mensuration",
        "forest protection",
      ],
      answer: "forest management",
    },
    {
      question: "In the context of plant nutrition, boron is",
      options: [
        "macronutrient",
        "micronutrient",
        "primary nutrient",
        "secondary nutrient",
      ],
      answer: "micronutrient",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a characteristic of pioneer species",
      options: [
        "ability to grow on bare rocks",
        "ability to tolerate extreme temperatures",
        "large size",
        "short life span",
      ],
      answer: "large size",
    },
    {
      question:
        "The climax near Tindni village is being controlled by disturbance by cattle. This is an example of",
      options: [
        "climatic climax",
        "edaphic climax",
        "disclimax",
        "catastrophic climax",
      ],
      answer: "disclimax",
    },
  ],
  quiz3: [
    {
      question: "Mechanical action of ocean waves is an example of",
      options: ["chemical weathering" , "physical weathering" , "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "physical weathering",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Khadar is a type of",
      options: [
        "black cotton soil",
        "alluvial soil",
        "saline soil",
        "red and yellow soil",
      ],
      answer:
        "alluvial soil",
    },
    {
      question: "In soil profile, C refers to",
      options: [
        "organic surface layer",
        "topsoil layer",
        "subsoil layer",
        "substratum layer",
      ],
      answer: "substratum layer",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Regur is a term for",
      options: ["black cotton soil", "alluvial soil", " saline soil", "red and yellow soil"],
      answer: "black cotton soil",
    },
    {
        question: "Bangar is a type of",
        options: [
          "black cotton soil",
          "alluvial soil",
          "saline soil",
          "red and yellow soil",
        ],
        answer: "alluvial soil",
      },
      {
        question: "Soil formation is dependent upon",
        options: [
          "vegetation",
          "time",
          "climate",
          "all of the above",
        ],
        answer: "all of the above",
      },
      {
        question: "Thermal stresses lead to",
        options: [
          "chemical weathering",
          "physical weathering",
          "biological weathering",
          "none of the above",
        ],
        answer: "physical weathering",
      },
      {
        question: "Carbonation is an example of",
        options: [
          "chemical weathering",
          "physical weathering",
          "biological weathering",
          "none of the above",
        ],
        answer: "chemical weathering",
      },
      {
        question: "Cryofracturing is an example of",
        options: [
          "chemical weathering",
          "physical weathering",
          "biological weathering",
          "none of the above",
        ],
        answer: "physical weathering",
      },
      {
        question: "Hydrolysis is an example of",
        options: [
          "chemical weathering",
          "physical weathering",
          "biological weathering",
          "none of the above",
        ],
        answer: "chemical weathering",
      },
    ],
};

export default quizSets;